

# Louise Bruland Bjerrum

PHD CANDIDAT

● she/her | ■ louise.bjerrum92@gmail.com | ② 0000-0001-5699-2780 | ② LouiseBjerrum | ⑤ louisebrulandbjerrum

PhD candidate at the University of Bergen, experienced in project planning, quantitative data collectionand statistical analysis, systematic reviews, and scientific writing. My main research interest is the effects of light on human cognition. I am also passionate about the R programming language for data wrangling, statistical analysis, and visualization of data.

### **Education**

MSc, Psychology - specialization in Behavioral Neuroscience	Norway
DEPARTMENT OF BIOLOGICAL AND MEDICAL PSYCHOLOGY, UNIVERSITY OF BERGEN	2015-2018
Philosophy	Norway
Norwegian University of Science and Technology	2014-2015
BSc, Psychology	Norway
Inland Norway University of Applied Sciences	2011-2014

# **Positions - current and previous**

#### PhD candidate

University of Bergen, Norway 2019-

#### Receptionist and group fitness instructor

Treningshuset, Norway 2018-2019

### **Teaching assistant**

DEPARTMENT OF BIOLOGICAL AND MEDICAL PSYCHOLOGY, UNIVERSITY OF BERGEN, NORWAY 2017-2018

### Group fitness instructor

Trene Sammen, Norway 2016-2017

#### Research assistant

DEPARTMENT OF BIOLOGICAL AND MEDICAL PSYCHOLOGY, UNIVERSITY OF BERGEN, NORWAY 2016

#### Research assistant

DEPARTMENT OF PSYCHOSOCIAL SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF BERGEN, NORWAY 2016

#### **Group fitness instructor**

SATS, NORWAY 2012-2014

#### **Receptionist and Community Support Worker**

SKOGLI HEALTH AND REHABILITATION CENTER, NORWAY 2009-2014

### Career breaks\_

2022-2023 Maternity leave

# Publications in international peer-reviewed journals

- 1. **Bjerrum LB**, Nordhus IH, Sørensen L, Wulff K, Bjorvatn B, Flo-Groeneboom E, Visted E. Acute effects of light during daytime on central aspects of attention and affect: A systematic review. Biological Psychology, 2024. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsycho.2024.108845
- 2. Visted E, Solbakken OA, Mæland S, Fadnes LT, **Bjerrum LB**, Nordhus IH, Flo-Groeneboom E. Validation of a brief version of the Difficulties in Emotion Regulation Scale (DERS-16) with an older Norwegian population. European Journal of Ageing, 2023. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10433-023-00775-w

### Published abstracts from international conferences \_

- 1. **Bjerrum LB**, Sørensen L, Osnes B, Visted E, Kambestad OB, Hansen ME, Nordhus IH, Bjorvatn B, Flo-Groeneboom E. The acute effects of artifical light on aspects of sustained attention. Journal of Sleep Research, 2024. https://doi.org/10.1111/jsr.14291
- Kambestad OB, Visted E, Osnes B, Sørensen L, Nordhus IH, Bjerrum LB, Flo-Groeneboom E. Exploring optimal light condiions for emotional processing in younger adults. IBRO Neuroscience Reports, 2023. https://doi. org/10.1016/j.ibneur.2023.08.1701
- 3. **Bjerrum LB**, Visted E, Nordhus IH, Lindholm SA, Flo-Groeneboom E. The acute effects of light on alertness, cognition, and mood: a systematic review. Journal of Sleep Research, 2020. https://doi.org/10.1111/jsr.13181
- 4. **Bjerrum LB**, Pedersen TT, Mrdalj J, Wisor JP, Marti AR, Rempe M, Henriksen TEG, Grønli J. Prolonged Photoperiod Induces Changes in Sleep: The Impact of Blue-Enriched Light. Neuropsychobiology, 2018. https://doi.org/10.1159/000489584
- Marti AR, Waslander J, Skrede S, Mrdalj J, Pedersen TT, Bjerrum LB, Ersland KM, Henriksen, TEG, Bramham C, Grønli J. Extended Photoperiod Alters Circadian Rhythmicity and Expression of Synaptic Plasticity-Associated Genes. The Impact of Blue-Enriched Light. Neuropsychobiology, 2018. https://doi.org/10.1159/000489584

## **Popular science communication**

1. Weinzaepflen C, Spitschan M, **Bjerrum LB**, Vethe D. Opplys klokken din: Hvordan kroppen vår holder styr på tiden [Enlighten your clock: How your body tells time, Transl]. Open Science Framework, 2021. https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.ID/35FVX

# Other relevant professional experiences\_

#### 2023-

WEB ADMINISTRATOR FOR BERGEN RESEARCH GROUP FOR INTERVENTION AND MENTAL HEALTH ACROSS THE LIFESPAN (BRIM)

Department of Clinical Psychology, University of Bergen

#### 2023

MEMBER OF A COMMITTEE CONDUCTING A SELF-ASSESSMENT OF RESEARCH ACTIVITY- AND QUALITY AT THE DEPARTMENT OF CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGY, IN RELATION TO THE RESEARCH COUNCIL OF NORWAY'S EVALMEDHELSE 2022-2024

Department of Clinical Psychology, University of Bergen

#### 2022

RESEARCHER REPRESENTATIVE IN A COMMITTEE CONDUCTING A BIOSAFETY RISK ASSESSMENT ON THE COLLECTION, STORING AND ANALYSIS OF SALIVA SAMPLES IN RESEARCH DURING THE PANDEMIC

University of Bergen

#### 2019-2022

PHD REPRESENTATIVE ON THE BOARD OF THE GRADUATE SCHOOL OF CLINICAL AND DEVELOPMENTAL PSYCHOLOGY

Department of Clinical Psychology, University of Bergen

#### 2019-2022

Administrative coordinator of Bergen Research Group for Innovation, Growth, Health, and Technology (BRIGHT)

Department of Clinical Psychology, University of Bergen

#### 2020-2022

TEMPORARY ACADEMIC STAFF REPRESENTATIVE IN THE DEPARTMENT BOARD

Department of Clinical Psychology, University of Bergen

#### 2019-2022

SUBSTITUTE SAFETY PREPRESENTATIVE

Department of Clinical Psychology, University of Bergen

#### 2019-2020

ORGANIZER OF TWO RESEARCH SEMINARS HOSTED BY BRIGHT

Department of Clinical Psychology, University of Bergen

#### 2017

ADMINISTRATIVE COORDINATOR OF A PHD SUMMER SCHOOL IN SLEEP AND CIRCADIAN RHYTHMS

Norwegian Research School in

Neuroscience

#### 2017

TRANSLATOR (FROM ENGLISH TO NORWEGIAN) OF A THERAPY GUIDE ON HARMFUL SEXUAL BEHAVIOR IN CHILDREN

Betanien hospital, Norway

### **Postgradute and PhD courses attended**

- 2024 Introduction to Practical Machine Learning in R, University of Bergen
- 2023 Software Carpentry Course: Shell, R, Version Control with Git, University of Bergen Library Digital Lab
- 2022 PsychR a course in statistics by using R, University of Bergen
- 2022 Quantitative Methods, University of Bergen
- 2021 Meta-analysis, University of Bergen
- 2021 Writing for Publication, Norwegian Research School in Neuroscience
- 2021 Theory of Science, Ethics, Methods, and Research Design, University of Bergen
- 2021 Basic course in web publishing on UiB's web platform, University of Bergen
- Sleep disorders: assessment and treatment of hypersomnia and sleep apneas, The Norwegian Medical
  - Association and Norwegian Competence Center for Sleep Disorders
- 2017 Animal Science Course (general), University of Bergen
- 2016 Animal Science Course (rodents and pigs), University of Bergen

# Skills and languages

R/RStudio: data wrangling, statistical analysis, data visualization, RMarkdown Experienced

SPSS: STATISTICAL SOFTWARE

Basic

GIT/GITHUB: VERSION CONTROL Basic

Microsoft Office: Word, Powerpoint, Outlook, Excel Experienced

ZOTERO: REFERENCE MANAGEMENT SOFTWARE Experienced

ACTIWARE: SCORING AND ANALYSIS OF ACTIGRAPHY DATA

Experienced

Norwegian, written and oral First language

Danish, written and oral First language

Fluent

ENGLISH, WRITTEN AND ORAL

### **Teaching experience**

During my PhD I have had course responsibility for an undergraduate course on the history of psychology as a science and a profession. I have also acted as external examiner in a variety of psychology courses at multiple higher educational institutions in Norway.

# **Supervision of students**

2022 Kine Marie Andersen Hillestad: Acute effects of blue light on alertness (MSc), co-supervisor

### **Conference attendance**

- 2024-09 27th Congress of the European Sleep Research Society, Seville, Spain
- 2020-12 Demensdagene, virtual
- 2020-09 25th Congress of the European Sleep Research Society, virtual
- 2019-09 7th National PhD Conference in Neuroscience, Bergen, Norway
- 2018-05 Society for Research on Biological Rhythms meeting, Florida, USA

### References\_

On request

### About this CV

This CV was generated with R version 4.4.1 (2024-06-14 ucrt) and the following package versions: - vitae: 0.6.0 - tidyverse: 2.0.0 - glue: 1.8.0 - tinytex: 0.53.